Why are the gangsters after you?
为什么黑社会要追杀你？
I don't know! I can't remember!
我不知道 我想不起来
What should I do to make you remember?
你要怎么样才能想起来？
The body found was
发现的尸体
Assistant Inspector, Tatsuhiko Akagi, 56 years old.
是警部补赤城达彦 56岁
Isn't the matter getting more serious?
总觉得这件事越来越夸张了
I am your class teacher,
我是你的班主任 藤代佐和子
This is Segawa. Sorry to bother you again,
我是濑川 抱歉 老是打扰你
but I'd like to know how Hikari is doing.
我还是想知道日花里怎么样了
MAUNTO
（山峰）
Have you seen my husband?
有见过我先生吗？
Hang on, what…
等等…
Oh? Chairwoman!
咦？班长
Wait…
等一下… 你不能来这烟雾弥漫的地方啊
Guys, have you seen my husband?
你们有见过我老公吗？
What?
什么？
-No… -What has he done?
-没有 -他怎么了？
Noriaki ran away from home.
典明离家出走了
What?
什么？
He seems to have always thought that I was pregnant but not with his children,
他好像一直觉得 这两个孩子不是他的
so we fought, and…
跟我吵了一架 就…
"To Momoyo.
“给桃代 我要踏上寻找目我…” 什么？
Sorry. "…take a look at myself again.
是“寻找自我之旅”
Please don't look for me. By Noriaki."
“请不要找我 典明”
So we have asked you to make time in your busy schedules to come here.
就是这个原因 我们请大家百忙中抽空聚集在这里
But it's impossible, because she is the Chairwoman.
其他人还可能 但班长绝对不会做这种事
The Chairwoman denied it, right?
班长否认了吧？
Who is the Chairwoman?
班长是谁？
She was like the Madonna to us.
是我们的女神
When we were at high school.
是我们高中时的女神
Madonna…
女神…
She is gorgeous, smart and nice.
她又美、又聪明、个性又好
The exact image of the Madonna.
简直是女神
Then why did she marry Tenten?
这么完美的人怎会嫁给典典哥？
That's…
那是…
One of the seven strangest stories in Numazu.
沼津七大不思议的其中一个
The marriage between a super idiot and the class president
超级笨蛋和班长的结婚 是个都市传说
So, why did Tenten say that?
那典典为什么会那么说？
It seems that the numbers didn't add up.
好像是日子不对
What?
什么？
He said that he didn't remember doing the act on the day
说是从预产期算回去时
when he calculated back from the due date.
他不记得那一天有做过那回事
I don't accept the reason.
我不接受这理由
It's impossible. Calculating backwards is too difficult for him.
算回去这种高难度数学 他根本做不到
Brave Tenten hadn't even learned his multiplication tables by high school.
典典前辈可是个到了高三 还念不好九九表的勇者啊
The problem isn't the multiplication tables.
问题不是九九表
The problem is that he suspects that the father is one of us.
是他在怀疑 我们中间其中一人是孩子的爸爸
-What?
-什么？
So what,
所以
you mean someone stole his wife?
是说我们有人给他戴绿帽？
No way. It's even more unlikely for the Chairwoman.
那就更不可能了 班长根本不会这样做
I'd like to think so, too.
我也希望这样想
But he's… I mean,
但那家伙…怎么说呢？
he's not smart, but his intuition is acute.
他人笨 但某方面的直觉很准
So let's make this clear here.
所以让我们在这里 把这事弄个明白吧
Crystal clear.
好好弄个明白
How?
怎么弄？
Guys, please close your eyes.
现在请各位闭上眼睛
Okay.
那么…
Raise your hand honestly if you made a cuckold of Tenten.
给典典戴绿帽的 诚实点举手
So?
咦？
If everyone has closed their eyes, who is going to check?
我们全都合上眼了 谁要看哪人举手？
Oh!
对啊
Well, I'll check.
我来吧
Only I am totally innocent.
就我一个完全不可能
Why?
为什么？
I didn't come back for ten years.
我走了十年了
-Does that count as alibi? -Of course!
-那能当证据吗？ -当然可以
I'm the one that's totally innocent. No matter how you look at it.
等等 我才是完全不可能吧？ 无论怎么想都是不可能
Really, this is ridiculous.
这实在是太白痴了
I'll go back to work.
我回去工作了
Frankly, you're the most suspicious one, Choco.
说真的 阿闪 你是最可疑的了
-What? Why? -It's your aura.
-为什么啊？ -是你的气场
You can't accuse me from my aura.
什么我的气场？
Your aura is impressive, Choco.
阿闪哥 你的气场很厉害
Exactly.
就是 这家伙 以前就一直散发他的强力气场…
Tenten didn't answer?
典典不接电话吗？
No, I was calling the teacher Hikari is staying with.
不是 我是打给带日花里走的老师
-You still can't contact her? -No.
-还是找不到她？ -对啊
I left a voice message, though.
不过我留了留言
Maybe she doesn't trust me.
她是不是起了疑心？
That's it, guys.
就是啊 你们几个
Hikari is more important than a guy running away from home.
日花里比大叔离家出走重要啊
-Huh? -Hikari's case is closed for me.
-什么？ -我觉得日花里的事告一段落了
Her teacher has brought Hikari home,
她的老师把她接走了
we'd better not bother them.
-也不要打扰她太多了 -说是这么说…
I feel uneasy parting from her without saying goodbye.
可是就这样分开了 我还是有点…
She said that she'd bring Hikari to see us soon, though.
她说过很快会来看我们的
I should have told Hikari your cellphone number. Sorry.
早知道就应该 把你的手机号告诉日花里 对不起
But speaking of which,
不过这样
you can't advance your relationship with an elementary schoolgirl!
你不可能跟她发展下去的 她是小学生啊
That's not what this is, idiot.
笨蛋 根本不是这回事
Well, I understand you, Keebou.
不 我懂的 希少
It's sad, isn't it?
真的很寂寞啊
When you break up with a woman she cries and pleads you not to go.
跟她分手的时候 那个女人哭着求你别离开她
And a week later…
然后一周之后
The feelings you get when you see her tweet,
看到她在推特上写上
"After the sad breakup, I finally know what true love is."
“克服了悲伤的爱情 才知道何谓真正的爱”的心情
Keebou.
希少
Can you take some time off on a weekday?
你能在平日抽时间出来吗？
Yes?
为什么？
Let's go to Hikari's school and have a look.
要去日花里的学校看看吗？
Don't be defeated until you win.
胜利之前绝不认输
You will surely win.
你一定能赢的
As long as you don't admit defeat,
只要不认输
you're only on your way to claim your victory.
你就永远在胜利的途中
That…
那个…
Will you let me see your whistle?
让我看看你的口哨吧
I can't see it clearly.
我看不清楚
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
This is expensive!
这个很贵的
Gosh!
真是的
Please don't kill me.
不要杀我
Don't do that. We can't kill her yet.
别这样 还不能杀她
Good gracious! I can't even go for a leisurely walk.
真是的 我想轻松地 出门走一下也不行
Mommy will take a shower. Make sure you keep a close eye on her.
妈妈现在去冲个澡 你好好看着她
Oh, right.
对了
I've bought your whistle candies.
你的口哨糖
Did you kill the policeman?
是你杀了警察叔叔的吗？
Why?
为什么？
Order.
命令
Order?
命令？
Your mom's?
你妈妈的？
That's awful…
怎么会…
KADOMATSU LIMITED
（门松兴业）
Keep a close watch on Kiichi Segawa.
彻底监视濑川希一
Plant it. The micro-sized bug.
装好这个超小型窃听器
You mean plant it on him, not in his room, don't you?
不是装在他家里 是装在他身上 对吧？
Plant it. The micro-sized bug.
装好这个超小型窃听器
But if I plant it on him we won't be able to trace him if he gets changed.
但就算装了 他一换衣服就没用了
How many times do I have to repeat myself?
混账 我要我说几遍？
Be aware of a crisis, airhead!
有点危机意识 白痴！
Okay.
知道了
I said you haven't put enough work into it.
我说过了 你还不够努力
You have to be creative, do you understand?
拿点创意出来好吗？
Okay. I'm sorry.
是 对不起
The only thing you can do is smile.
你啊 就只懂得笑 工作就完全…
This is very creative.
这就是创意吧？
-You again? Get lost, idiot! -Manager!
-是你？笨蛋 快走开 -店长
I'm a customer now, so it's rude to say that to me.
我现在是客人 你这样说话…
Gosh! All the staff in this supermarket are idiots!
真是的 这超市里全都是笨蛋
What is this, the kingdom of idiots?
这是笨蛋王国吗？
If this is the kingdom of idiots, then you're the king of idiots.
要是这里是笨蛋王国的话 你就是笨蛋国王了啊
Thank you, Mr. Watchman.
谢谢你 保安员先生
Why?
为什么？
It's a bit early for this, but…
这个是早了点 不过…
HALF PRICE
（半价）
Is that all right?
没关系吗？
Don't tell anyone.
别告诉别人
Pichan, please! I want to buy this!
小屁 拜托 我想买…
Madame Saya, 200,000 yen is really too much.
纱彩大人 20万实在太多了 饶了我吧
But it's on special offer!
可是这是特价啊 帕斯卡路还能唱歌呢
TALKING ROBOT PASCAL 3RD
（帕斯卡路三号）
But you have Chappy, the ventriloquist's dummy.
你不是有用腹语的恰比了吗？
But ventriloquism is difficult!
可是腹语很难啊 好吗？拜托你
They can't replace it.
这些都不能代替啊
Both Chappy and Pascal can't replace a child…
恰比和帕斯卡路也不能代替孩子啊
Of course I know that.
这么简单的道理我也知道啊
I mean, why not?
这样不好吗？
I enjoy it.
我很快乐啊
I enjoy being alone with you forever.
就算一直是跟你两人在一起
Pichan.
小屁…
Have you washed your hands?
你洗手了没？
Is it really okay for you to come now? Your husband…
这时间真的没问题吗？ 你先生不会发现吗？
You have to work during the day, right?
但你不是说这阵子白天都要工作吗？
Yeah, a daytime staff member went AWOL.
因为白天打工的有一个搞失踪
And tomorrow?
明天呢？
We don't have to meet every day.
不是每天见面也可以吧？
Say, a meteorite is going to crash on Earth.
如果有陨石要撞上地球了
Yes? What are you talking about?
什么？你在说什么？
You have a ticket for the spaceship that will escape from the Earth,
你有一张票 可以登上一艘逃离地球的宇宙飞船
but I don't.
可是我没有 你会怎么办？
I'll give you the ticket.
我会把那张票让给你
-I don't want that. -What?
-我不要 -什么？
On the other hand, if I have the ticket and you don't
如果相反 我有一张票 而你没有
I will… burn the ticket.
-我会把那张票烧了 -烧了？
I will choose to stay with you on the Earth as it dies.
我会选择和你一起 留在快毁灭的地球上
If I choose not to give you the ticket
那如果我选择不把那张票给你
and board the spaceship…
然后登上宇宙飞船呢？
I will destroy the spaceship.
我会破坏宇宙飞船
That is how I express my love for you.
这就是我爱你的方式
This is not love.
那才不是爱
Shuntaro…
春太郎？
That's not love! It's something else!
那才不是爱 是别的东西
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry…
对不起…
Don't hate me, Shuntaro.
不要讨厌我 春太郎
I'm lonely!
我很寂寞
I'm lonely…
我很寂寞 我真的很寂寞
Mr. Tagawa?
田川先生？
Hey.
是你啊
What's the matter?
怎么了？
I've come to say hello.
我是来跟你道别的
I'm thinking of quitting the mob and leaving this town.
我打算金盘洗手离开这地方了
Really? Why so suddenly?
真的假的？怎么这么突然？
It's pointless doing this.
-我觉得很没意思 -什么？
I've worked very hard in this world for ten years,
我在这世界努力了十年
yet what I got is this little town in the countryside.
换来的只是这小小的乡镇
But I still wanted to guard my territory,
就算是这样 我也下了决心要尽力要保护这领土
But…
可是…
my pride is nothing
我这个人的尊严 对本部的人来说跟本不值一哂
They won't even realize if they've crushed me.
甚至连把我踩扁了也不会发觉
Also,
而且…
after I met you again, you made me realize…
跟你再见之后 我才发觉一件事
Realize what?
什么？
How much more capable you are than I am.
你比我厉害多少
That's nonsense.
哪有这回事？
I'm exhausted, Patrasche.
我累了 帕托拉休
Patrasche?
帕托拉休？
A Dog of Flanders!
是《龙龙与忠狗》啊！
Oh…
这样啊…
This is my farewell gift.
这是饯别的礼物
What? I can take this?
你要送这个给我吗？
I think it'll suit you.
我觉得跟你很合
Thank you! I will treasure it.
谢谢你 我会珍惜它的
Take care, then.
那你保重了
Mr. Tagawa.
田川先生…
I mean, Chancellor, take care!
不…总长 你也要保重
Oh, welcome back.
欢迎你回来
Thanks. Welcome back.
我回来了 欢迎回来
Thanks.
我回来了…这…
Wow, this is lovely.
真的很不错
-Greeting someone when you're home. -Yeah?
-回家跟人打招呼 -是吗？
Especially when you say, "Welcome back".
尤其是有人欢迎我回来
Doesn't the girl say that?
那孩子不会说吗？
Well…
那个…
She is not staying with me now.
她已经不在了
Ask him where she is now.
快问他那女孩现在在哪里
Are those charm stones?
你那个是能量石吗？
Is that what they're called?
是这么叫的吗？
Is it a gift from your girlfriend?
是女朋友送的？
No, I haven't got a girlfriend.
不是 我没女朋友
Oh.
对了
You can have it if you like.
你想要的话就拿去吧 这种东西我比较那个…
How can you give to her?
别送给别人 你不是说会珍惜它的吗？
Why did you say you don't like it?
什么叫“那个”啊？
Oh… It's all right. Don't bother.
这…不用了 我不要 这上面刻了龙
Yeah…
说的也是啊…
It's a bit…
这个有点…
Yeah.
就是啊
I'm glad that you have bad taste.
还好你的品味够差
Cheers.
是…
Thank you for your help!
谢谢你救我
I love you, Keebou!
我最喜欢希少了
Good grief.
怎么了？
Eat your tomato, too!
别剩下蕃茄
It's him again? Such a pest.
又是他？烦死了
You have a message.
这是给您的留言
This is Segawa. Sorry for bothering you again.
我是濑川 抱歉 老是打扰你
I really want to know how Hikari is doing,
我还是想知道日花里怎么样了
so I'll now go to your school.
所以我现在会去学校
I just want to see Hikari's cheerful face somewhere.
我只希望在远处 看到日花里有精神的样子
-Sorry for that, Chairwoman. -It's totally okay.
对不起 班长 老是麻烦你
HAYASHIDA LAUNDRY SHOP
（林田洗衣店）
You guys are still as close as you used to,
你们感情还是这么好
going on a road trip all by yourselves.
几个男人一起去兜风
We'll look for Tenten along our way.
我们顺便去找典典吧
Don't bother, just leave that idiot.
你们就别管那笨蛋了
He's going to be a father! I can't believe him.
明明快要当爸爸了 实在是太胡闹了
Sorry, we're late. I've borrowed the van.
不好意思 来晚了 我们借车子来了
Thanks…
谢谢
She is absolutely gorgeous!
她的水平真的好高
Why did she marry Tenten?
那么好的人为什么会嫁给典典哥？
You'll understand how charming Tenten is soon, too, Melos.
梅洛斯 你很快也会知道典典的魅力的
Yeah, when Tenten isn't here, we're not ourselves, too.
没错 典典不在的话 我们也有一点…
If he isn't here people will see how stupid we are.
他不在的话 其他人就会知道我们笨
Why have you brought snacks?
你们带糖果干嘛？
We're not going to hike.
我们不是去远足
-We are going hiking! -Oh?
-是远足吧？ -这…
I didn't notice your bracelet before.
希少 你之前有戴那手链吗？
This? Tagawa gave it to me.
这个？是田川给我的
What?
什么？
He said it was a farewell gift.
是饯别的礼物 他说要金盘洗手
Seriously?
真的假的？
This is fishy.
真可疑
Has he planted a bug or something?
会不会装了窃听器之类的？
Impossible.
不可能的
He's not like that.
他不是那种人
I'm so jealous! It's so cool!
那手链好棒 好酷
Do you want it, Melos?
那送给你吧 梅洛斯
I don't like accessories.
我还蛮那个的
Don't give it to him!
别给他啦！
And how dare you say you don't like it?
还有 “那个”是什么意思？
Oh, it's from the teacher.
老师打来了
Yeah. She has a high fever.
对 就是那样 她发高烧
So much happened lately, I guess she is tired.
发生了这么多事情 可能是太累了
I've taken her to see a doctor today,
我今天带她去看医生
so I'm sorry, but she won't be going to school.
真不好意思 她不在学校
Is Hikari at your house now?
那日花里她现在在你家？
Yes.
是的
Will you let me talk to her?
可以让我跟她说一下话吗？
Keebou…
希少？
Hikari!
日花里
She said you had a fever. Are you okay?
她说你发烧了 没事吧？
Yeah, I'm all right.
我没事
How are you, Keebou?
你还好吗 希少？
I'm good. The guys are good, too.
我很好 大家都很好
Hi, Hikari…
-嗨 日花里 -日花里
Are you eating properly?
有好好吃饭吗？
I'm all right.
我没事
I want to have the stewed beef you made again!
我好想再吃希少你弄的炖牛肉
What? Stewed beef?
什么？炖牛肉？
I made it.
那是我啊
-Mikki made the stewed… -I am all right!
-炖牛肉是米奇… -我没事的
Make me stewed beef again, Keebou!
希少 再弄炖牛肉给我吃
Oh, Hikari, thanks for the origami medal.
对了 日花里 谢谢你的纸奖牌
Thank you for your lovely message, too.
看到你写的东西我也很高兴 谢谢你
Keebou.
希少
You've taken it? Thank you.
拿了 谢谢你
Taken what?
拿了什么？
-Hello. You're happy now? -Oh…
-是我 已经够了吧？ -啊…
Can I go to visit her?
那个…我能去看看她吗？
That's not…
那个有点…
The doctor said that we can't let her get too excited.
医生说过不能让她受大多刺激
Keebou!
希少
PHOTO!
（照片！）
Then can you at least send me a photo of her?
那能至少发一张照片给我看吗？
Photo?
照片？
Please.
拜托你
Okay.
我知道了
Good grief!
真是的
He even asked for a photo. How much cheekier can he be?
还要照片？他脸皮到底有多厚？
Come on. I'll take a photo, so smile.
来 拍照了 笑一个
Don't make that face! They'll get suspicious.
不行啊 你那个样子他们会怀疑的
Smile!
笑一个
Don't you think it is strange?
她感觉很奇怪 对吧？
Yeah.
很奇怪
Why did she say "stewed beef"?
什么炖牛肉？
Maybe she really liked it?
可能是太好吃了吧？
I told you, it was me who made her stewed beef.
我说了 弄的人是我
And one more thing.
还有一点
"You've taken it? Thank you."
“拿了 谢谢你”？
I think she was talking about the origami medal…
我想她是指这奖牌
THANK YOU FOR YOUR HELP! I LOVE YOU, KEEBOU!
（谢谢你救我 我最喜欢希少了）
Hikari.
日花里
-What is that? -It's whistle candy.
-这是什么？ -是口哨糖吧？
Whistle candy?
-口哨糖？ -没错
-You don't know that? -It's called the generation gap.
-你不知道是什么？ -这叫代沟
Guys.
对了
I think she lied about something that Keebou would know was a lie.
她可能是特地说了个 希少会知道的谎话
I mean the stewed beef.
那个炖牛肉
What do you mean, and why?
-什么意思？ -为了什么？
To let you know that she is lying.
让我们知道她在撒谎
Did she talk about the stewed beef
她是在说她没事之后 说炖牛肉的吧？
So in other words…
那就是说…
I think she meant that she was not all right.
我想她是说她有危险
Oh!
这…
What's the matter, Melos?
怎么了 梅洛斯？
Is it possible that… "You've taken it? Thank you"…
难道说“拿了 谢谢你”是说…
If you take away "thank you"…
如果拿掉“谢谢你”的话…
Look!
你看
SAVE
（救我）
Ms. Sawako Fujishiro is on leave today.
藤代佐和子老师今天请假了
I see.
是吗？
She said that she was going to the hospital.
她说她要去医院
Do you know where Ms. Sawako Fujishiro lives?
那个 藤代老师的地址…
I can't tell you.
这个我不能告诉你
Thought so.
也对…
But we've confirmed that the teacher is real.
不过确定了那老师是真的了
Yes, I've checked that, too.
那个我也确认过了
It's impossible that a teacher would hang out with gangsters.
老师怎么可能跟黑道混在一起？
We've overthought it.
是想太多了吧？
She didn't call for help.
“救我”之类的
We were as smart as Ikkyu, though.
刚才我们可是跟一休和尚一样聪明
Right, Melos?
对吧 梅洛斯？
Oh.
哦
It's Hikari.
是日花里
-What? -Look!
-什么？ -你们看
HAPPY! JOYFUL! SMILE!
（开心、愉快、微笑）
Oh, it is her.
真的是她
SMILE WITH MS. SAWAKO
（和佐和子老师一起远足）
We took it when we went hiking last year.
是去年远足时拍的
Mikki?
米奇？
Hey…
你干嘛…
I'm sorry, Keebou!
希少 对不起
What's the matter, Mikki?
怎么了 米奇？
She deceived me.
我被骗了
I was deceived.
-什么？ -我被她骗了
That woman…
那个女人…
is not a teacher.
根本不是什么老师
What?
什么？
Why don't you kill her?
你不杀他吗？
No one ordered me to.
没有人命令我
Will you kill her if someone orders you to?
有人命令你的话 你就会杀吗？
I will.
会杀
You'll kill me, too?
连我也会杀吗？
You don't…
你不会讨厌…
hate killing?
杀人吗？
Why?
为什么？
Killing people is wrong!
因为杀人是不对的 不是吗？
Hey!
喂！
Don't get so close, you two!
你们两个分开一点
You! Don't seduce my son!
你别勾引我家儿子
Kids nowadays are horrible.
最近的小孩还真可怕
If you have time to bat your eyelashes at him,
你有时间向他抛媚眼
remember where it is now!
就快点想起来 我们没有时间了
It's those guys again? They're such a nuisance!
又是那些家伙…真的好烦
Oh!
这是…
Hello.
你好
Sir?
大师？
Yes, I have got her.
我抓到她了
No, her memory is still…
是的 她的记忆还没…
Yes?
什么？
The mountain?
山里？
Sure.
是
I've received an order. We're going out.
收到指令了 我们要出去
Where to?
去哪里？
To the place where you were. Mount Nakane.
你之前去过的地方 中根山
What?
什么？
I told you I didn't have time.
我说过 我们没时间了
Maybe you'll remember something if you go there.
你去了那里说不定能想起些什么…
Does he have something else…
大师又有什么…
It's those guys.
是他们啊？
Let's go.
走了
No, she isn't answering the phone.
不行 她不接
Darn!
真可恶
I want to at least tell Hikari that we're aware of her message.
至少让日花里知道 我们发觉了她的暗示
I think it's important.
我觉得这对她来说很重要
So that she won't be downhearted.
让她这里不会认输
The woman doesn't know that we have realized that,
那个人应该不知道 我们已经察觉不对劲了
so she might answer the phone next time.
所以她可能还会接电话
Mikki.
米奇
The fake teacher was a middle-aged woman, right?
那个假教师是中年女人 对吧？
Get in.
上车
Oh, my!
讨厌
Hello?
你好
-You're joking! She really answered it! -This is ridiculous!
-不是吧？她真的接了 -太荒谬了吧？
You're incredible, Choco.
阿闪哥 你太厉害了
This really is the last time.
这次真的是最后一次了
Please understand that.
请你们明白
This is for Hikari's own good.
这是为了日花里好
Okay.
好的
I understand that.
知道了
Hello.
是我
Keebou?
希少？
Hikari.
日花里
We got it.
我们知道了
We understand it very well.
我们都非常清楚
We got what you said.
我们都懂你要说的话
Hikari.
日花里
We will all come to see you.
我们一定会一起去找你的
So before we do so, no matter how tough it is,
所以 在我们来之前 无论多么辛苦
don't be defeated, Hikari.
都不要认输 日花里
You remember it, right?
你记得吧？
As long as you don't admit defeat,
只要不认输
you're just on your way to claim your victory.
你就永远在胜利的途中
Keebou!
希少…
Hikari…
日花里
Don't give up until you win.
在胜利之前别认输
Mount Nakane!
中根山！
-What? -Mount Nakane…
-什么？ -中根山…
-Drive the car here! -All right!
-快准备车子来！
-Mount Nakane… -Stupid brat!
-死小鬼！
Now I will do anything to make you remember!
既然这样 我就是用尽办法也要让你想起来
Mikki, drive safely, okay?
米奇 注意驾驶安全
It's a total loss if we're caught speeding!
超速被抓的话 就赔了夫人又折兵了
Mikki, be careful!
米奇 你小心点啊！
HAYASHIDA LAUNDRY SHOP
（林田洗衣店）
This is her car. It has to be.
是这车子了 不会错的
Hikari!
日花里…
It's here.
就是这里了
MT. NAKANE HIKING ROUTE
（中根山登山道）
Which way should we go?
是哪边？
-Keebou! -Yes?
-希少 -什么？
Look.
你看这个
It's a miracle that you fell down from here
你从这里跳下去也没受伤 简直是奇迹
I fell down from here?
我掉下去了？
But there won't be a second miracle.
不过 同一个奇迹不会发生两次
You will die right away if you fall this time!
这次掉下去的话 你就死定了
Think! Try to remember!
快 想起来
Where is it?
哪里？那东西在哪里？
No!
不要！
You hid it somewhere in this mountain, didn't you?
你把它藏在这山里 是吧？
I don't know! I don't!
我不知道…
Remember it! Now!
快点想起来 快点
I don't know!
我不知道
Hikari!
日花里
You're lying about having amnesia, aren't you?
你说你失去记忆其实是骗人的吧？
Tell me!
快说 把你记得的都说出来
Please don't do this!
不要
I know you're the last person who had it.
我知道最后拿着它的就是你
Help me! Keebou!
救我 希少
Keebou!
希少！
Hikari!
日花里！
-Keebou… -Hikari!
-希少… -日花里
Shut up!
闭嘴
Don't come here!
你们别过来
If you get any closer, I'll throw this brat down.
你们再走过来的话 我就把这小鬼扔下去
Give us back Hikari, please!
把日花里还给我们 拜托你
Of course I won't give her to you, idiot.
我怎么可能还给你？笨蛋
No, you will.
我们会要你还的
How dare you lie to me, old hag?
居然敢骗我 你这该死的老太婆
Kill him!
杀了他
No!
不要
Don't kill Mikki!
不要杀米奇
Don't kill anyone!
不要杀人
Kill him now!
快杀了他
This is an order!
这是命令
No!
不要
You're actually very kind, aren't you?
你其实人很好的 不是吗？
You gave me whistle candies!
你给了我口哨糖 不是吗？
You didn't want to kill the policeman, right?
你其实不想杀警察叔叔的 不是吗？
It was you…
就是你？
You killed Mr. Akagi!
就是你杀了赤城先生？
-Jerk! -No! He is dangerous!
-混账！ -不要 他很危险的！
-Ponjara! -Are you all right?
-碰将 -你没事吧？
It's useless. He is a professional.
你们做什么都没用 因为他是职业的
What? Professional?
什么职业的？
What else? He's a professional killer.
还会是什么？他的职业是杀人
An assassin!
是个杀手
Kill them now! This is an order!
快杀了他们 这是命令
No!
不要！
Don't kill them!
不要杀他们！
Do it. Do you want to disobey mummy's order?
快去 你不听妈妈的命令吗？
Don't obey this! This is wrong!
你不能听！因为这是不对的
-Killing people is wrong! -Shut up!
-杀人是不对的！ -闭嘴
You have to repay him.
我们要报恩
Who is the reason why the two of us can live so long?
是多亏了谁 我们母子俩才能活到现在？
The Hierarch.
大师
Yes. Good boy.
对 好孩子
Don't do this!
不要！
Do it now!
快杀他们
If you want to kill, kill us yourself!
要杀你自己来杀！
I don't know why you have to repay that person,
我不知道你在说什么报恩
but no mother would make her own son a killer!
但哪有母亲 会要自己的儿子去杀人的？
You don't
你那样…
deserve to be his mother!
根本不配当母亲！
Shut up!
你闭嘴！
You know nothing about us.
你什么都不知道
Don't you patronize me!
就别教训我
My son…
这孩子跟普通的孩子不同
Everybody ran as soon as they knew this.
大家知道了之后 就全都逃得无影无踪
My husband and my parents abandoned us.
就连我先生和父母也是
But only the Hierarch…
但只有大师…
Hierarch?
大师？
Only he
只有大师在我孤单一人 走投无路时伸出援手
He was the only one in this world to do this.
这个世界上 就只有他一人…
All of you are irresponsible
你们浑浑噩噩地过日子
and all you do is bring your parents trouble. You won't understand!
只会给父母添麻烦 你们又知道什么了？
The Hierarch…
大师他…
found him a kindergarten, a hospital,
帮他找幼儿园、医院…
and more importantly, he gave him a way to live!
最重要的是 大师赋予了他生存的道路
So that he can live even when I'm not with him.
就是我不在他身旁时 他还能生存的路
And that's…
你是说…
You said that way was to work as an assassin?
你是说那条路就是当杀手？
Being an assassin is better than dying a dog's death!
杀手又怎么样？总比惨死街头要好啊
Of course it isn't!
那怎么可能？
It's okay to kill because you have to live?
你们为了生存就去杀人
-That's not… -Then what should we do?
-怎么可能… -那你教我怎么办
We have to do this.
我没办法啊
We had to do this.
我实在是没办法了
Or…
还是你说你们会帮助我？
Will you take care of my son for the rest of his life? Tell me.
你们会照顾我孩子一生？怎么样？
Will you give us enough money for him to live the rest of his life?
你们会给我够他花一辈子的钱吗？
My son's life…
比起其他人的生命 自己孩子的生命才是最重要的
This is the life that I treasure!
自己珍惜的生命才是最重要的
I don't care about the other ones!
其他的我管他干嘛？
Now,
快 杀了这些家伙
-This is an order. -No!
-这是命令 -不要
Don't kill them!
不要杀他们
I'll kill him.
我来杀
I will kill him.
我会杀了他
Even if we will die on each other's swords,
如果能让日花里和他们活下去
I will kill your son so that Hikari and the guys will live.
就算是同归于尽 我也要杀了你儿子
Do you still think…
就算是这样 你还能说是没办法吗？
You are right.
你说得对
The life you treasure
比起其他人的命
is more important than other people's.
自己珍惜的才是最重要
But…
可是…
Other people's lives…
其他人的生命 也是某些人很珍惜的生命
Isn't this sad?
不是很可悲吗？
If someone you treasure dies,
如果自己珍惜的人死了
the sadness is unbearable.
会伤心得不能自已啊
Why did you make your son
他是你儿子
someone who gives people such sadness?
为什么要把他变成 制造这种悲伤的人？
It's okay.
没关系的
He doesn't understand this.
因为他根本不懂
He doesn't have a heart that can feel emotions like that!
他根本没有一个能感受这种感情的心
You're wrong!
才不是这样
He was very kind.
他对我很好
He taught me how to blow the whistle candy!
他还教我怎么吹口哨糖
He has killed a lot of people!
他已经杀了无数的人了
Without even flinching.
他可是连眉头也没皱一下
Is someone with a heart even capable of that?
一个有心的人能做出这种事情吗？
He only wanted to make you happy.
他只是想让你高兴而已吧？
He only…
他只是…
wanted to make his mother happy.
想让妈妈高兴而已
Because he loves his mom.
因为他爱妈妈
Loves…
爱？
He loves me?
他爱我？
It's impossible.
不可能的
-His mother is so awful… -No matter how you are as a mom,
-像我这么过分的妈妈… -不管你这母亲是怎么样
children just love their mother.
孩子还是会很爱妈妈的
He just wants to make you happy.
他只是想妈妈高兴
So desperately…
太想让妈妈高兴了…
that even if he has to betray his friends
就算是要背叛同伴
he would do anything to make his mother happy!
孩子还是会想尽办法来让妈妈高兴的
-Keebou! -Hikari…
-希少 -日花里
They must have suffered a lot.
他们的日子一定很难熬吧？
Okay. Thanks for your work.
好 辛苦你们了
Give me the kid.
把小鬼交出来
Hey.
你好啊
You are the puppet in the rumors?
你就是传说中的木偶吗？
Although you are as strong as a demon
虽然像怪物一般强
you can't do anything if no one orders you.
但是没人命令的话 就什么都做不了
What is going on?
这是搞什么？
Aren't they allies?
他们不是一伙的吗？
I don't know!
我怎么知道？ 希少 带着日花里一起走
Come here.
给我过来
Keebou!
希少
Hikari!
日花里
-Go to hell! -Don't!
-去死吧 -快住手！
Mommy?
妈妈？
I was told to kill anyone on that side as soon as I saw them.
他们吩咐过 一看到你们那边的人就要干掉
On that side?
“你们那边”？
Don't come here!
不要过来
No…
不要
Help!
救我
Don't kill me!
不要杀我
I won't kill.
不杀
I know.
我明白了
Why I shouldn't kill…
为什么杀人是不对的…
Because it is sad.
是因为会伤心
If Mommy dies…
如果妈妈死了
If she is not with me…
不在我身旁了
I feel sad.
我会伤心
We will take care of the rest.
我们会处理之后的事情
But can we at least see whether he is alive or not?
可是 我希望至少看看他是生是死
The sound of a gunshot reached even here.
枪声连这边都能听到
The police will come soon.
我相信警察应该很快会来的
Go! You'll cause us trouble.
快走 不然会很麻烦
What was that?
刚才的…
A bird?
是小鸟？
Hikari.
日花里
He must still be alive.
他一定还没死
Mamoru…
真守…
HAYASHIDA LAUNDRY SHOP
（林田洗衣店）
Okay…
好吧…
Noriaki…
典明
Where have you been?
你到哪里去了？
You…
桃代
I have been thinking.
我想过了
I'll embrace it. I don't care whose children they are,
我会接受的 不管他们是谁的孩子
your children are mine… Ow!
桃代的孩子就是我的孩子…好痛
They are your children!
是你的孩子
But I…
可是我…
I can't believe this.
我不能相信啊
How can someone as good as you…
像你这么好的女孩
fall in love
-怎么可能喜欢像我这样的… -相信我吧
I love you, Noriaki! I really do!
我爱你 很爱你
I love your everything, even how stupid you are!
我爱你的所有 连你的笨也爱
Momoyo!
桃代…
Well, I…
我…这是…那个…
I'm sorry!
对不起
-Tenten. -Yes?
-典典 -嗯？
-Wash it! -Oh…
-给我洗了它 -等等…
I'm happy to!
我很乐意
NEW MESSAGE
（新信息）
Oh, it's from Kiichi.
是希一发的？
FROM KIICHI. THANK YOU, MOM.
（妈妈 谢谢你）
What a surprise.
怎么突然说谢谢？
Sir…
大师…
Don't stress yourself.
不要勉强自己
I'm very sorry.
真是对不起
We cannot…
我们两个已经…
Don't worry about it.
不要紧的
Thanks for everything you've done.
一直以来 辛苦你们了
Have a good rest.
好好休息吧
I have really been horrible
我对你们母子 实在是做了很过份的事情
Sir…
大师
Thank you.
谢谢你
But…
那个…
Where is Mamoru?
真守呢？
Where is my son?
我的儿子…
Oh, don't worry.
不用担心
You will see him soon.
你很快就会见到他了
Thank you.
谢谢你
Sir…
大师
Thank you…
非常…
very…
谢…
You will meet Mamoru very soon.
你很快就会见到真守的…
In heaven.
在天国里
Lives are on the line, Keebou.
这会出人命的 希少
We can't win.
我们这次毫无胜算
Leave now if you won't take part.
想离开的就趁现在
Are you in some trouble about that incident?
说不定他因为那件事惹上麻烦了
It's weird that we still can't find her.
还没找到 太不合理了
Sorry for dragging you into this.
对不起 把你们拖下水了
Thanks for everything.
过去承蒙关照了